Jules Ponsaillé

27 rue du Docteur Finlay 75015 Paris France

+33 6 95 33 25 96jules.ponsaille@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ponsaille/ github.com/ponsaille/

Objective

To obtain a 6-month research internship in Computer Science

Scientific interests

I am most interested in computer vision, general-purpose GPU programming and programming in general. I also developed a strong interest in problematics linked to earth and satellite imagery through my experience at the French Ministry of Ecology. Finally, I am reading a lot about web performances.

Education and diplomas

ISEP

Graduate Software engineering studies

Sep. 2018 - Now

Paris, France

Paris, France

Preparatory class (Math, Physics and Engineering)

Sep. 2016 - Aug. 2018

Lycée Janson de Sailly

High school diploma (major in science)

Paris, France Aug. 2016

Work Experience

French Ministry of Ecology

Paris, France

- Intern at the research and innovation department for the GreenTech verte Jul. 2019 Dec. 2019
 - Worked with startups: Automated 3D maps generation for Ecodele, realized data analysis on currents and watermills to create a map for VH-Quatre-Vingt-Treize and realized an audit on Ealico's Website
 - Search for existing data on a project to detect all water retention with satellite imagery
 - Wrote an administrative note addressed directly to the interdepartmental delegate for sustainable development about the need of pesticides reduction and solutions based on computer science proposed by French startups
 - Was part of the pilot to create a center of innovation on Data, AI, Nudge and OpenInnovation (Ecolab) in the Ministry
 - Helped redesign communication tools for the GreenTech verte: automatized the generation of the startups' repertory, created an interactive map, ...

ISEP's IEEE Student Branch — Garage ISEP

Paris, France

Head of CoderLab (laboratory about algorithms and programming)

Jun. 2018- now

- Co-created CoderLab
- Helped add websites' accessibility to ISEP's curriculum
- Democratized hackathons and algorithmics contests at ISEP by creating and leading two teams and designing algorithmic contests
- Arranged sponsorships with Bearing Point, Thales, etc.

- Taught Javascript

Latitude Association

Ambassador at ISEP

Paris, France Nov. 2019 - now

- Promote Tech For Good projects
- Organize conferences and workshops
- Integrate socials and environmental issues in the curriculum

Junior ISEP (IT Consultancy)

Paris, France

Consultant — Front-end developer in React.js and Vue.js

June 2017 - July. 2018

Projects

Relativity4GPS

Paris, France

ISEP

Mar. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- Simulation of the effects of relativity on the GNSS satellites or any other satellite of the earth.
- Developed understanding on GNSS systems and algorithms

Creation of an automated babyfoot for training purposes *ISEP*

Paris, France

Sept. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- Created a custom color-tracking algorithm for the web based on WebGl
- Developed skills in computer vision and electronics

Enigma and its cryptanalysis before Turing ISEP

Paris, France

Sept. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- Studied and demonstrated mathematical theorems from Rejewski's work
- Modelled Enigma in Python and Javascript

Skills

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, MathLab/Octave, Java, HTML, CSS, PHP
- GIS: QGis, GeoPandas
- Electronics: Arduino, Raspberry Pi
- Publication: LaTeX, Office, Photoshop, Illustrator, Davinci Resolve
- Web Frameworks: Node.js, React.js, React Native, Vue.js
- Soft Skills: Project Management, Organized, Adaptability to new environments (Lived 4 years in Belgium)

Scientific activities

- Board of sustainable digital startups jury at the French Ministry of Ecology
- Attended the conference about introduction to program verification at ISEP organized by IEEE and Garage ISEP
- Attended the presentation of the "Report on the environment states" at the French ministry of ecology

- Attended the presentation day of the C3S service of Copernicus at the French ministry of ecology
- Attended to the "COLLOQUE SCIENTIFIQUE DE CENTRALESUPÉLEC of 2019" (Scientific conferences of CentrealeSupélec) and represented IEEE France as a member of the IEEE Student Branch.

Prizes

- Nuit de l'Info 2018: "Digital assistance of an explorer in extreme conditions" (In Team)
 - 1st place for FabSpace 2.0's challenge: "Usage of geospatial data"
 - 1st and 2nd places for Accenture's challenge: "Coop Mode"
- Nuit de l'Info 2017: "On the way to party" (In Team)
 - 1st place for Altran's challenge: "Du code à la sauce Google Docs"
 - 1st and 2nd places for DAHER's challenge: "VR l'infini et l'au delà!"

Languages

- French (Mother Tongue)
- English (TOEIC: 975)
- Dutch (4 years in Belgium)
- Spanish (Scholar)
- Chinese (Beginner)

Hobbies

- Sports: Tap Dance and Kite-surf
- Algorithms Contests: IEEEXtrem (287/4000 teams), BattleDev, ...
- Hackathons: Nuit de l'Info 2017 (2 prizes), Nuit de l'Info 2018 (2 prizes), Nuit du Code Citoyen, TechCrunch of Vivatech
- Reading: Science-fiction, Barjavel, Hunger Games, ...

Primary References

Maria Trocan IEEE France Vice-President responsible of Student Activities; Associate Professor, ISEP, maria.trocan@isep.fr